翻译校对       Mam
日  听      HARERE
日听校对       Syura
翻译        阿里斯
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
The beach?
海？
Yes, the beach!
イエス　海
The beach...
海
You said so before, didn't you?
この前言ってたじゃん
You wouldn't mind going
to a real beach.
本物の海なら行ってもいいって
Did I say that?
言ったっけ
Yes, you did. And so...
言いました　というわけで
...we've prepared some swimsuits for you.
水着を用意してみました
Isn't this cute?
かわいいだろう
僕は　こういうのがハルちゃんには似合うと思うなあ
I think...
...that this would look good on Haru-chan.
ちっちっちー
You don't get it, huh, Honey- senpai?
わかってないね　ハニー先輩は
Just wearing this uniform
helps to gloss over the fact
この　制服を着ただけでごまかせてしまうまな板具合
"Little Miss A-cup"
that she's as flat as a cutting board.
A one-piece type suit like
that would only invite tears,
ワンピースタイプじゃお粗末極まりない体型まるわかりで
by making it obvious how
utterly poor her figure is.
涙を誘うね
On that point, we carefully
selected this separate-type suit.
その点　僕らが厳選したこのセパレートタイプは
The frills do a fine job of
covering the absence of any bust!
フリルで胸の無さを見事にカバーするのであります
何をうちの娘にセクハラしまくってるか貴様らは
How dare you guys heap sexual
harassment on my little girl!
That's enough of that!
いい加減にせい
Then, we aren't going to the beach?
じゃ行かないの　海
Whoever said we weren't going?
だれが行かんと言った
Oh, then you do want to go!
何だ　やっぱ行きたいじゃん
Can Usa-chan come, too?
ウサちゃんも一緒
I have no objections.
異論はないな
Huh? We're really going?
え　本当に行くの
Come on, let's go to the beach!
いざ　海へ行こう
"The Sun, the Sea, and the Host Club!"
So, why Okinawa?
で　何で沖縄
鏡夜ん所の　プライベートビーチもあるしな
Kyoya's folks have a private beach here.
綺麗なところだね
It's a beautiful place, huh?
Yeah.
But as long as we're
going somewhere, why not...
でもどうせなら
カリーブとか
...the Caribbean...
...or Fiji?
フィージーとか
Do you think Haruhi has a passport?
ハルヒが持っていると思うか　パスポート
- Ahh...
- Thank you so much for
your thoughtfulness.
お心遣い痛み入りますが
It's so pretty.
綺麗ね　環君と二人で海が見れるなんて　夢みたい
Tamaki- kun, being alone with you,
looking out at the sea, is like a dream.
It's no dream.
But if I could have my way,
夢じゃないさ　だけど　願わくば今夜
I'd wish that I could appear
in your dreams tonight.
あなたの夢に僕が現れますように
Tamaki- kun...
環君
Take it easy, Hikaru!
手加減してよ光
Sorry! I'll get it!
悪い　僕が行くよ
Wait for me, Kaoru!
待てよ馨
It's not me! The ball is running away!
僕じゃないよ　ボールが逃げるのさ
"Hosts working on location"
Why?
なぜだ
Your two-shot time is up. Next, please.
ツーショットタイム終了です　次の方どうぞ
Why are we conducting Host Club
activities here at the beach?
なぜ海に来てホスト部の活動を
Haruhi- kun...
ハルヒ君
Haruhi- kun, aren't you going swimming?
ハルヒ君は泳がないの
Oh, I like looking at the sea more.
海は見てる方が好きなので
Well, would it be okay if we joined you?
じゃ私たちもご一緒してよろしいかしら
How come?
どうして　泳いできなよ
Go ahead and swim.
You're wearing such
cute swimsuits, and all.
せっかく可愛い水着着てるのに
We were completely fooled, huh?
完全に騙されたよね
Who'd have thought he'd
bring guests with us?
まさか客まで呼んでるとは
We really didn't figure on that.
本当計算外
I invited you club members
along for free,
お前たち部員はただで招待してやったんだから
so be sure to perform your services.
しっかりサービスに務めてくれよ
But with guests here...
しかも客がいたら
...Haruhi won't be able
to wear her swimsuit.
ハルヒに水着は着せられない
Everything has been taken into account.
全ては計算通り
Did you think that I would let
my dear little girl in her swimsuit
誰が可愛い娘の水着姿をお前らの目になど晒すものか
be exposed to your eyes?
"The Theatre of Tamaki's Mind"
And then, come sundown,
そして夕暮れになったら
Haruhi and I will take a stroll,
just the two of us, along the shore.
ハルヒと二人きりで波打ち際をお散歩するのだ
It really is a pretty sunset.
本当綺麗な夕日
I wish we could stay here like
this and watch it together forever.
いつまでもこうして一緒に見ていたいですね
Or something along those lines!
That would be just too much, huh?
なんちゃったりなんかしてもう　たまりませんな
What could have come over Tamaki- kun?
環君はどうなさったのかしら
Don't worry about it.
気にしないで
It's his usual condition.
いつもの病気だから
Haru-chan!
ハルちゃん
Let's go hellfish shunting!
ヒヨシガリしよう
I think you mean "shellfish hunting."
それを言うならシオヒガリ
And I've never heard of anyone
going shellfish hunting...
大体こんなとこで潮干狩りなんて話　聞いたことないですけど
...anywhere like this...
What is this!?
何ですかこれは
Mori- senpai...
モリ先輩
My folks' private police force
我が家のプライベートポリスが
wanted to make up for their offense
toward Honey- senpai earlier,
この前のハニー先輩に対する非礼を詫びたいということですので
so I'm letting them do this.
勝手にやらせています
Amazing! What a haul!
すごい　大漁だね
We're going to have a fancy
side dish tonight, huh?
今夜のおかずは豪華ですね
美味しそう
It's going to be delicious!
"Brimming with happiness"
Well, you two look like you're enjoying
yourselves, so I guess it's all right.
ま　二人とも楽しそうですし　いいんじゃないですか
Senpai!
先輩　今夜の晩ご飯は大漁ですよ
We caught a big haul for tonight's supper!
そうかそうか　我が娘よ
You did, you did, my little girl?
A big haul! A big haul!
大漁ですよ　大漁ですよ
Huh? What was that?
なんだ？
Tonight's supper is going
to be a real treat!
今夜のご飯はごちそうですよ
What do you think, Haruhi?
Do you find this large crab to be...
どうだハルヒ　でっかいカニさんは　好きカニ
...crab-tivating?
Yes.
好き
How cute!
かわいい
Cen...
...ti...
...pede!
Hey, Haruhi...
おい ハルヒ
As much as it would pain me
百歩譲って　お前が虫好きの心優しい少女だとしてもさ
to think that you're a bug-
loving, kindhearted girl...
...couldn't you have at least
set that thing free more gently?
せめてそっと離してやるとかないわけ
It's okay. It will take
more than that to kill it.
大丈夫だよ　あれぐらいじゃ死なないって
Haruhi- kun is so manly.
ハルヒ君男らしい
And yet so nice, huh?
それにやさしいのね
Fantastic!
素敵
Well, okay, fine.
まあいいけどさ
Usually, though, girls
react quite differently.
普通の女の子とはだいぶ反応が違うな
Isn't there anything
she's afraid of?
あいつに怖いものはないのか
Sir! Sir!
殿　殿
面白いゲーム考えたんだけど参加する
We just thought up
a fun game. Want to play?
We call it...
題して『誰がハルヒの弱点を見つけられるでしょうか』ゲーム
...the "Who can find
Haruhi's weakness?" game!
What an awful-sounding game.
何って悪趣味な遊びだ
Yeah, you're probably right.
そうだよね　弱点なんて親しい者にしか見せないし
She'd only show her weakness to
someone she was close to, and all.
What are the rules!?
ルールは
そうこなくちゃ
That's more like it.
The deadline is tomorrow at sunset.
期限は明日の夕方
Whoever finds out what her
weakness is first, wins.
先に弱点を見つけた方の勝ち
I will give whoever wins a prize.
勝った者には俺から賞品を出してやろう
We're in on this, too!
僕らも混ざる
So then, everyone is playing.
それでは全員参加ということで
But Kyo-chan, how is it that
you have those photos?
でもキョウちゃん　何でその写真持ってんの
I have my sources. Why don't
we just leave it at that?
とある筋から　とだけ申し上げておきましょうか
"And so..."
"Let the games begin!"
This place here...
ここはさ　地元の人でもめったに通らない心霊スポットなんだって
...is said to be a paranormal spot,
which not even the locals
will come to very often.
It's a cave that only
shows itself at low tide.
引き潮の時にしか姿を現さない洞窟なんだけど
Up to now, they say that a lot
of people have drowned down here.
これまでも多くの人が溺れ死んでるらしくて
They say that their lingering resentment
drags passers-by into the dark.
その人達の怨念が 闇に通行人を引き込むらしい
What's that there!?
何だあれは
What is this? A test
of courage or something?
何これ　肝試しかなんか
Aren't you afraid of ghosts?
お前さ　お化けとか怖くないの
I've never seen one.
見たことないからね
"Paranormal fear strategy...
failed"
Haru-chan! Over here, over here!
ハルちゃん　こっちこっち
Um...
あのう
Is this thing even allowed
to be on the beach?
こんなもの浜辺に入れちゃっていいんですか
Okay, private police people,
if you please!
それじゃ　プライベートポリスの皆さん　お願いします
暗いよ　狭いよ　怖いよ
It's dark, and confined, and scary!
- Honey- senpai...
...and confined, and scary!
ハニー先輩
"Claustrophobia attack strategy...
failed"
暗いよ　狭いよ　怖いよ
It's dark, and confined, and scary!
This is a mori, right,
''Mori: harpoon"
これって銛ですね　モリ先輩
Mori- senpai?
"A play on words?"
Yeah.
"Fear of sharp objects strategy...
failed"
This game is useless, huh?
無理だねこのゲーム
Ah... I'm getting bored.
なんかつまんねえ
She's not cut out to be a heroine,
あんだけ怖いものないって
with all those things she's not afraid of.
ヒロインとして失格じゃないの
Oh...
- Sir?
- What are you doing?
殿　何してんの
Rat snakes! Having this many
together has to be icky, right?
青大将だ
これだけ集めると気持ち悪いだろう
Anyone would find those unpleasant.
That's not a weakness.
そんなの誰でもキモイよ　弱点じゃない
Then again, does Okinawa
even have rat snakes?
でもさ　沖縄に青大将なんていたっけ
And another side dish...
おかずゲット
Haruhi- kun!
ハルヒ君
Hey there!
This breeze feels great!
風が気持ちいいよ
It's dangerous up there.
危ないですよ
This feels great, huh?
気持ちいいね
Mm-hmm.
Oho, there are girls up here!
こっちにはギャールいるじゃん
Lucky! Hey girls, let's play together.
ラッキー
彼女たち　一緒に遊ぼうよ
What are you people doing here?
何ですかあなたたちは
いいじゃん　女の子ばかりじゃつまんないでしょう
Who cares? It must be dull having
no one but girls around, huh?
Please stop. This is a "private beach."
やめてください　ここはプライベートビーチですよ
なにそれ　お嬢様ってやつ
What's that? Does that mean "sweethearts"?
痛ぇ
Ee-yow!
Would you go away now?
They don't want you.
離れてくれませんか
嫌がっているでしょう　迷惑だと言っているんです
They say you're bothering them.
Haruhi- kun...
ハルヒ君
Why, you little kid...
このガキ
Habu snakes!
Those are habu snakes, sir!
"Habu: a poisonous snake
indigenous to Okinawa"
ハブだ　それハブだよ殿
What do I do!?
どうしよう　こんなに捕まえちゃって
環様
Tamaki-sama!
It's Haruhi- kun!
ハルヒ君が
なんだよ　この細い腕は
What's with these spindly arms?
Haruhi- kun!
ハルヒ君
Don't go trying to act tough
when you're such a sissy boy!
女みてぇなくせに　格好付けじゃねぇよ
Kid, you should just
go swimming in the ocean...
ガキはおとなしく海水浴でも
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
...like a good boy!
してろ
Haru-chan!
ハルちゃん
Sir!
殿
Where are they?
あいつらは
We've kept their ID cards,
and respectfully asked them to leave.
身分証を預かって 丁重にお帰りいただいたよ
The girls went back to the hotel.
女の子たちはホテルに帰った
I've called a doctor,
who should be here shortly.
医者は呼んであるから　すぐに来てくれるだろう
I see.
そうか
I'm all right.
I don't need a doctor.
大丈夫ですよ　医者なんて
Are you one of those?
お前はあれか
Actually a martial arts master,
like Honey- senpai?
実はハニー先輩みたいに　武道の達人だったりするわけか
How could you think that you,
a girl, by yourself,
女の自分一人で
男を相手になんとかできるってどうして思うわけ
could do anything against those boys!?
It had nothing to do with
being a boy or a girl.
男とか女とか関係無いでしょう
I was just there, and didn't have
time to think about anything like-
あんな所に居合わせて　そんなこと考えてるひま…
Well think about it, you idiot!
You are a girl!
ちょっとは考えろバカ　お前は女なんだぞ
I will apologize for making
you come after me,
迷惑かけたのは謝りますけど
but I can't understand any other
reason why you'd be mad at me.
それ以外で怒られる意味が分かりません
I haven't done anything wrong.
間違ったことはしていない
You haven't, huh?
Then you go right ahead.
そうかよ　それなら勝手にしろ
I'm not speaking to you again
until you admit you were wrong!
間違いを認めるまで　お前とは口をきかん
"The Otori family villa"
Ta-da!
The crabs are all boiled!
カニ　茹であがったよ
I'm sorry, Senpai, that there
aren't any maids here now.
すみません先輩　今メイドがいなくて
We're the ones that barged
in on your villa, Kyo-chan.
キョウちゃんの別荘に押しかけちゃったの僕らだし
Takashi, go call Haru-chan in.
崇はハルちゃん呼んできて
It's awfully gloomy out there, huh?
It looks like it might rain.
なんかすごく暗いよね　雨でも降りそう
Speaking of gloomy...
暗いって言えばさ
There's someone even more gloomy
in here than the darkness outside.
ここに 外の闇よりもっと暗い人がいるよ
そんなに落ち込むなら　喧嘩なんか売らなきゃいいのに
If you're going to mope like that...
...then you shouldn't have
picked a fight with her.
Haruhi, did you buy that dress yourself?
ハルヒ　その服自前？
My dad must have
repacked my bags for me.
父が勝手に荷物詰め替えたらしくて
He always wants me
to wear stuff like this.
こういうのばかり着せたがるんだよね
Good job, Haruhi's dad!
グッジョブ　ハルヒ父
"Ha-ru-hi's Dad!"
Haru-chan, you look cute.
ハルちゃんかわいい
The air is stuffy, huh?
空気悪いよな
It's kind of tense in here.
なんか　張り詰めてる
Let's eat, Haru-chan!
食べよう　ハルちゃん
I'm sure the crabs we
caught today are delicious.
今日取ったカニさ　きっと美味しいよ
"A play on words?"
These crabs...
このカニは　うまいカニ
...taste in-crab-ible.
Get it?
なんちゃって
Aren't you eating too much,
to say the least?
いくらなんでも　食べ過ぎじゃないか
Huh? I thought you
weren't speaking to me.
あれ　口きかないんじゃなかったんですか
"Snap!"
Y-you're not being cute.
かっ　かわいくない
Okay, I get it. You're not going
to reconsider what you've done.
よくわかった　反省する気はないらしいな
Fine, then. I'm going to bed.
もういい　俺は寝る
Kyoya, show me to my room.
鏡夜　部屋まで案内してくれ
All right. Well, if you'll
excuse me, too...
分かった　じゃ俺もお先に失礼する
Maybe I really should learn
some karate or something.
やっぱり空手とか習ったほうがいいのかな
女の自分一人で
How could you think that you,
a girl, by yourself,
男を相手になんとかできるってどうして思うわけ
could do anything against those boys!?
Oh, then it is bothering you?
何だ　気にしてんじゃん
That's the direction your
thoughts are going, is it?
そっちに行くわけね　お前の思考は
It's not like we'd
stop you, or anything,
そりゃ別に止めないけどさ
but that's not what this
is about, is it?
そういうことじゃないだろう
To be honest, I wish you'd reconsider
how rashly you acted today, too.
正直　今日みたいな無茶は　僕も反省して欲しいけどね
Why? Hikaru, I didn't make
trouble for you guys, did I?
なんで　光たちには迷惑かけてないじゃん
That's not true, Haru-chan.
違うよハルちゃん
You should tell everyone
you're sorry, okay?
みんなにごめんしよ　ね
Understand? And tell
Tama-chan that you're sorry
いい　タマちゃんにもいっぱい心配かけてごめんねって言うんだよ
for worrying him so much, too.
You were all worried about me?
心配してたんですか　みんな
Do you believe this girl?
この子は
Oh...
そっか　ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
Aww, what for, you little mutt?
もう　なにこの小動物
You're so cute, we'll forgive you!
かわいいから許す
"Squeeze"
What's the matter?
どうした
I don't feel so good.
気持ち悪い
You ate too much crab.
カニ食べ過ぎ
ハルちゃんしっかり
Haru-chan, be strong!
Come on, over to the washroom!
The washroom!
ほら洗面所行って洗面所
What a wasteful thing I've done.
もったいないことをしてしまった
I was in such a rush, I just plunged
into the nearest room. Where am I?
慌てて手近な部屋に飛び込んじゃったけど
ここって
All done?
済んだか
I'm sorry for intruding into
the room of a stranger...
すいません　見ず知らずの方の部屋に
How rude. It's me.
失礼な　俺だ
Kyoya- senpai?
鏡夜先輩
Oh, I'm sorry, I seem to have
gotten everyone worried about me.
すいません　なんか皆さんに心配かけたみたいで
I wasn't particularly worried.
俺は別に心配などしていない
It was hard to stop Hikaru and Kaoru
ただ　光と馨があの不良連中を半殺しにしようとするのを止めるのは
from trying to beat those
punks half-to-death, though.
大変だったけどな
Also, there was the trouble I went
to sending bouquets to the girls
後は　せっかくこの旅行を楽しみに来てくれた女の子たちに
by way of apology, after looking
forward to coming along on this trip.
お詫びの花束を送る手間がかかったぐらいだ
I'll pay for those flowers myself.
その花代は自分が払います
The bouquets cost 50,000 per
person, so it comes to 600,000.
一人あたま　５万の花束だから　しめて６０万になるぞ
Why did you turn the lights off?
なんで電気を
If you want to, you could pay
for those flowers with your body.
なんならその花代　体で払ってもいいぞ
You should rethink your own
gullibility, that things
男も女も関係ないという自分の甘さを見なおすことだな
have nothing to do with
a person being a boy or a girl.
You've made a mistake
in leaving yourself so open.
あまりに無防備なのは　お前のミスだ
So that's it.
そっか
Kyoya- senpai, you won't do it.
鏡夜先輩はしませんよ
I mean,
だって　自分に手出しても何のメリットもないでしょう
there isn't anything to be gained
by getting into it with me, right?
True enough.
確かに
You are indeed fascinating.
まったく　面白いね　お前は
But I did find out one thing.
でもよくわかりました　鏡夜先輩が意外にやさしいってことが
Kyoya- senpai, you're even
nicer than I thought.
After all, you were just backing
up what Tamaki- senpai said, right?
だって今の　環先輩へのフォローなんでしょう
Well think about it,
you idiot! You are a girl!
ちょっとは考えろバカ　お前は女なんだぞ
You intentionally played the bad
guy to show me that, didn't you?
わざと悪役に回って　教えてくれたんですよね
Kyoya?
鏡夜　ローションあるか
Do you have any lotion?
This sunburn is worse than I thought-
日焼けが意外にきつく…て
Kyoya, you rotten...
鏡夜お前
ほら　勝手に使え　バカが
痛い　痛い　痛い
Here. Use as much as you want, you goof.
Nothing to be gained, eh?
メリットね　それなりに興味深い感想だ
An interesting thought, in its own way.
What were you doing with Kyoya?
鏡夜と何をしてた
Nothing, really.
別に何も
You expect me to believe it was nothing!?
何もってことあるか
Then how come the room's lights were
out and you two were all alone!?
じゃなんで部屋の光を消して二人っきりで
You are positively...
だいたいお前は
Never mind. A lot has happened today,
and you must be tired,
もういい　きょうはいろいろあって
お前もつかれてんだから　さっさと寝ろ
so hurry on off to bed.
Senpai...
先輩
Er, I mean...
Haruhi?
ハルヒ
I'm sorry.
すいません
I just remembered something I have
to take care of, so if you'll excuse me...
ちょっと用事を思い出したので　これで失礼します
Nobody has any business in there!
そんな所に用のある子はいません
Haruhi, can you not stand thunder?
Come on, Haruhi, get out here.
ハルヒ　お前雷だめなのか
こらハルヒ出てこい
Staying in there makes it that
much more scary, doesn't it?
そんなとこに入ってたら余計怖いだろうが
I'm all right. I always get
through it by doing this.
大丈夫です　いつもこんな感じで乗り切ってますから
Always...
いつも
Always, by yourself...
いつもたった一人で家の中で
in your home...
without calling on us,
even though we're nearby...
俺たちが近くにいるのに呼びもしないで
I see.
そうか
I think I get it. Okay, I lose.
なんか分かった　いいよ　俺の負けだ
You grew up without
relying on anyone else.
お前は人に頼らずに育っちゃったんだな
So, come on...
だからほら
Come on over here.
こっちに来いよ
From now on, I'll be there.
これからは俺がいる
I'll do all I can not to take
my eyes off of you,
お前が一人にならないように
to make sure that you're
never alone again.
せいぜい目を離さないことにするよ
Are you sure this is okay?
本当に大丈夫だったの
Leaving the two of them together?
二人きりにして
She's with our Tamaki.
What could possibly go wrong?
相手はあの環だぞ　どんな間違いが起こるっていうんだ
Sir? We're coming in.
殿　入るよ
You see? With the blindfold,
you can't see anything,
は耳栓をすれば
and sound-wise, if you wear earplugs...
Ah, you're right!
本当だ
Despicable.
最低
- What kind of "-play" is this?
- l-it's not like that!
何プレーですか
違う　違うんだあ
It's not like that!
Be careful, Haruhi.
気をつけろよ　ハルヒ
His highness apparently
has a thing for S&M, too.
殿はSMの趣味もあるみたいだから
I told you, it wasn't like that!
だから違うと言うとろうが
I see. So that's what S&M is.
そっか　あれがSMっていうのか
知らずに変なことさせられちゃったなあ
I let you get away with something
funny without even knowing it.
It wasn't like that!
I did it for your sake!
違うだろう　俺はお前のために
Start driving.
出してくれ
Hey!
Don't leave me behind!
俺を置いてくな
Wait!
待ってよ
何で今まで気づかなかったんだ
ハルヒってめちゃくちゃ女子高向きじゃないか
Why have I never noticed it before?
Haruhi is totally cut out for
an all-girls' school, isn't she?
だからって女子高に転校するなど絶対に許さん
Which is why there's no way I can
let her transfer to a girl's school!
Next time, "A Challenge
From Lobelia Girls' Academy"
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
お待ちしております